Paetel, Karl O.; Papers ger072
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence, 1940-1984; 2
  - Correspondence with Organizations, Institutions, 1941-1981; 2.4
    - Emergency Rescue Committee / International Rescue and Relief Committee, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Film-Amateur-Club Hamburg e.V. (Adolf Reimer), 1947 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Foreign Press Association, 1963-1972 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Freideutscher Kreis, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Freiheitsbund Deutscher Sozialisten. Rundbriefe (Kurt Hiller), 1942-1945 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Freiwirtschaftsbund für natürliche Ordnung von Kultur, Gesellschaft und Wirtschaft, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Friends of German Labor (Erich Schmidt), 1960-1964 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - German Consolate General, 1952; 1968 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Geschwister-Scholl-Stiftung (Inge Aicher-Scholl), 1951-1957 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Gruppe "Opposition", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Institut für wissenschaftliche Politik der Philipps-Universität, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Institut für Zeitgeschichte (Werner Röder), 1953; 1956; 1972-1980 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Institute for Central European Research, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Institute of Social Research, 1943; 1947 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Internationaal Institut voor Sociale Geschiedenis, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - International Biographical Centre, 1975-1978 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - International Relief Association, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - International Student Service, 1941-1944 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Internationaler Schutzverband deutschsprachiger Schriftsteller (ISDS) / Schutzverband der Schriftsteller deutscher Sprache im Ausland (SDS), 1953-1975 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Jewish Immigrants' Aid, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - The League for Mutual Aid, 1944; 1968; 1971 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - The Library of Congress, 1943; 1971 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - N.A.A.C.P. Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc., Undated (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - National Refugee Service, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - New School for Social Research, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - New York Friends' (Quaker) Subcommittee on Food Parcels for Europe, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Office of Price Administration, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Office of War Information, 1942-1944 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Overseas Press Club of America, Inc., 1963 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - P.E.N. Club, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Radical Education Project, Undated (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Selfhelp of Émigrés from Central Europe, Inc., 1938; 1942 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Unitarian Service Committee, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - United States Government Coordinator of Information, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - The Universal Christian Council, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Vereinigung der Verfolgten des Naziregimes (V.V.N.), 1947 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Wandervogel, Undated (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Writers' War Board, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 68)
- Manuscripts by Paetel, ca. 1940-1982; 3
  - Autobiographical Writings, Undated; 3.1
    This series contains manuscript versions of Paetel's autobiographies, Ein Deutsches Tagebuch and Reise ohne Uhrzeit, both of which were published posthumously. Also included in this series are texts of several autobiographical essays.
    - Ein Deutsches Tagebuch. T. with numerous h. corr., pp. 1-161, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ein Deutsches Tagebuch. T. with numerous h. corr., pp. 162-331, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Ein Deutsches Tagebuch. Pc., pp. 1-132, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Ein Deutsches Tagebuch. Pc., pp. 133-311, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Ein Deutsches Tagebuch. Working title: "Heimkehr? Als ich vor 15 Jahren Deutschland wiederseh. Tagebuchaufzeichnungen eines deutschen Exilierten," pp. 1-132., Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Ein Deutsches Tagebuch. Working title: "Heimkehr? Als ich vor 15 Jahren Deutschland wiederseh. Tagebuchaufzeichnungen eines deutschen Exilierten," pp. 133-333, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Ein Deutsches Tagebuch. Working title: "Heimkehr? Als ich vor 15 Jahren Deutschland wiederseh. Tagebuchaufzeichnungen eines deutschen Exilierten," pp. 171-199, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Ein Deutsches Tagebuch. Fragments, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – "Prälude." T.cc. with numerous corr., Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – "Prälude." Early versions., Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – Chapter: "Jugend." T.cc, 1906-1930 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – Chapter: " Berlin." Early version, 1932-1933 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – Chapter: " Berlin." Later version, 1932-1933 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – Chapter: " Berlin." Several versions. T.cc, 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – Chapter: "Prag." Early versions. T. and T.cc., Undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – Chapter: "Prag und Berlin." Multiple copies. T.cc., 1935 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – Chapter: "Skandinavien." Multiple copies. T.cc., 1935-1936 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – Chapter: " Paris." Multiple copies. T.cc., 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – Chapter: "Transit." Multiple copies. T.cc, 1940-1941 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – early fragmentary versions. T. with numerous h. corr.; T.cc, Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit – fragments, Undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit. T.cc. of complete text, Undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit. Pc. of complete text, Undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit. Pc. of text used for publication, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit. Pc. of text used for publication, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit. Nachwort by Wolfgang D. Elfe, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Reise ohne Uhrzeit. Autobiographie. Hrsg. u. bearb. v. Wolfgang D. Elfe u. John M. Spalek. Worms: Georg Heintz, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Das 'Auslandsbüro der Gruppe Sozialistische Nation'." T. and cc. 2 versions. 5p., 6p, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Gespräche mit Deutschen. Ein Aussenseiter spricht mit Aussenseitern." T.cc. 5, Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "I was a Prisoner in Spain." Text in German. T.cc. 16p, Undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "Im Lande des Je m'en foutismus." T. 3p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Meine Begegnung mit Heigru, tusk und der Gestapo." Pc. 5p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "New Yorker Brief an einem Berliner Freund." T.cc. 3p, Undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - "Wiederbegegnung – ein persönliches Fazit nach 15 Jahren." T. with h. corr. 11p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "Die Zeiten ändern sich, nicht wahr?" Oder: Heimat und Exil." 5 c. T. and cc. 1p. ea., Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - "Der 20. Juni 1934. Persönliche Aufzeichnungen von Karl O. Paetel." T. and cc. with h. corr. 8p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Manuscripts of Books and Longer Published Works, Undated; 3.2
    The series includes among others, manuscript materials to: Beat. Eine Anthologie, Das Bild vom Menschen in der deutsche Jugendfhrung, Jugendbewegung und Politik, Jugend in der Entscheidung, Versuchung oder Chance?, as well as Paetel's works concerning Ernst Jnger.
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. "Amerikas Beat Generation." T. with numerous h. corr. 24p. T.cc. 2c. 22p. ea., Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. "Bibliography." T.cc. with some h. corr. 24p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. "Inhaltsverzeichnis" [Beat. Eine Anthologie]. Pc. and cc. 32p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. "Einführung." Early version. T. with numerous h. corr. 47p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. "Einführung." T.cc. 40p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. "Amerikas 'Beat Generation'. Eine Anthologie." Herausgegeben und eingeleitet von Karl O. Paetel. Deutsche Fassung von Willi Anders. T. with numerous h. corr. 225p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. "Kurzbiographien"; "Quellen-Nachweis." T. with numerous corr. 18p. T.cc. 34p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. "Beat-Diktionaer." T.cc. 10p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. Notes, miscellaneous pages. 11p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. pp. 1-103. T. with h. corr., Undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. pp. 104-200. T. with h. corr., Undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. pp. 201-313. T. with h. corr., Undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. pp. 314-393. T. with h. corr., Undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Beat. Eine Anthologie. "Bibliographische Hinweise." T. with h. corr. 53p. Galley proofs. 24p, Undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Das Bild vom Menschen in der deutschen Jugendführung. Pc. of manuscript, dated 1954. Pages numbered 1-56. (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Das Bild vom Menschen in der deutschen Jugendführung. Synopsis, notes. 15p, Undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Deutsche Innere Emigration. Anti-Nationalsozialistische Zeugnisse aus Deutschland. Dated New York. Bound T. with clippings. 69p., 1946 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Ernst Jünger. Eine Bibliographie. Various versions. T., T.cc. and pc. 48p., Undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Bound volume containing manuscript versions of: Ernst Jünger. Die Wandlung eines deutschen Dichters und Patrioten; Ernst Jünger. Weg und Wirkung; Ernst Jünger. Eine Bibliographie; and Ernst Jünger in Selbstzeugnissen und Bilddokumenten., Undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Jugendbewegung und Politik. Randbemerkungen. Pc. of manuscript 165p., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Jugend in der Entscheidung Page proofs., 1913-1933; 1933-1945 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Jugend in der Entscheidung "Persönliche Vorbemerkung." T. and T.cc. with corr., 1913-1933; 1933-1945 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Jugend in der Entscheidung "German Youth yesterday, today and tomorrow." Outline of English version. T.cc. and mimeo. 5p. ea., 1913-1933; 1933-1945 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Jugend in der Entscheidung "Deutsche Jugend. Gestern, heute und morgen" T. with numerous h. corr. 296p., 1951 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Jugend in der Entscheidung "Deutsche Jugend. Gestern, heute und morgen." Pc. of manuscript., 1913-1933; 1933-1945 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Jugend in der Entscheidung "Deutsche Jugend zwischen gestern und morgen. Ein Kurzbericht über die Abwehr neonazionistischer Tendenzen am Rande der Jugendarbeit durch die demokratischen Jugendverbände der Bundesrepublik." T.cc. 100p., 1913-1933; 1933-1945 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? "Der deutsche Nationalbolschewismus." T.cc. with numerous h. corr. 15p. Another copy entitled "Der deutsche Nationalbolschewismus. Ein Bericht." Multiple copies. T.cc. 15p., 1910-1932 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? Early chapter outlines, some duplicates. A., T. and T.cc. 56p., 36p., 31p., Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? Versuchung oder Chance? Zur Geschichte des deutschen Nationalbolschewismus. T. with h. corr. 128p, Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? Early chapter versions. T.cc., Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? Unidentified pages. T.cc., Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? Pages from earlier versions, incorporated into final version. T.cc., Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? "Vorbemerkung"; "Der Hamburger Nationalkommunismus." T.cc., Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? Bound manuscript. T. with numerous corr. Hand-paginated, p. 1-385. "Dokumente" and "Bibliographie." Unpaginated. 70p., Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? Page proofs: Chapters I-V., Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? Galley proofs: Chapters VI-end., Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? Galley proofs: Chapters VI-end., Undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Versuchung oder Chance? Galley proofs: Dokumente., Undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Longer Manuscripts, Unpublished, Undated; 3.3
    arranged alphabetically by draft manuscript title.
    Included in this section are also early versions of works which later evolved into published works.
    - "Amerika. Randbemerkungen an Ort und Stelle." Collection of published and unpublished essays. T.cc. with some corr., clippings, dup. pages.275p, Undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "Karl O. Paetel. Aufsaetze (Auswahl)." Planned collection of published essays. Bound collection of clippings., 1939-1953 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - "Bibliographie des deutschen Widerstands gegen Hitler." T. and T.cc. with numerous h. corr. 70p., Undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "Die deutschen Widerstandsbewegung gegen Hitler. Eine vorlaeufige Bibliographie." Several copies. T.cc. 13p., Undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - "Brevier der Unruhe." Planned essay volume. T.cc. Ca. 200p, Undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - "Dokumente des Deutschen Widerstands gegen Hitler." Outlines. T.cc., Undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "Dokumente des Deutschen Widerstands gegen Hitler." Pc. Ca. 300p., Undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "Das Dritte Reich und seine Gegner. Dokumente des deutschen Widerstands gegen Hitler," pp. 1-94. T. and T.cc., Undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "Das Dritte Reich und seine Gegner. Dokumente des deutschen Widerstands gegen Hitler," pp. 95-209 (pages missing). T. and T.cc., Undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "Das Gesicht des Anderen Deutschland. Das politische Exil in Wort und Bild." Planned essay volume, with photos of Hans Sahl, Arthur Koestler, Siegfried Aufhäuser, Emil J. Gumbel, Anna Siemsen, Gerhard Seger, Bertolt Brecht, René Fülöp-Miller., Undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "Die Hitlerjugend. Material zur Frage totalitärer Jugendführung." T. and T.cc. with numerous h. corr. 100p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Heinrich Himmler and his Terror-Army" (in English), pp. 1-59; (in German), pp. 60-215. T. with corr., Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "Heinrich Himmler and his Terror-Army" (in German), pp. 216-421. T. with corr., Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Heinrich Himmler und die SS." Appendix. T. and T.cc.161p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "The German SS in Arms (Waffen-SS). Appendix to 'Hitler's Lost Army'." T.cc. 144p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Heinrich Himmler und die SS." Appendix. T.cc. with corr. 139p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Heinrich Himmler und die SS." Appendix. T.cc., Undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "Anhang. Daten zur Geschichte der SS." T. and T.cc. 18p. Notes. 2p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "Die Buergerkriegsarmee des Nationalsozialismus: Die Waffen-SS." T.cc. 32p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Die SS. Ein Beitrag zur Soziologie des Nationalsozialismus." T. and T.cc. with numerous h. corr. 50p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "Hitler's Black Army: The 'Waffen-SS'." T.cc. with corr. 16p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - ["Heinrich Himmler and the SS"]. Speech text, in English. T. 16p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - "Hitler's Black Vanguard." T.cc. 51p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - "Hitler-Reden." Excerpts, chronology of Hitler's speeches. T.cc. 42p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - "Structure of the German Government, the NS-Party, and the Wehrmacht." T. 28p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "Die Herrschaft des Schwarzen Ordens." T. and T.cc. with numerous h. corr. 49p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "Hitlersche Wehrmacht." Various chapters, duplicates, mostly T.cc. Ca. 250p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - "Waffen-SS." Miscellaneous document texts., Undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "Biographien." Short biographies of prominent Nazis. T. and T.cc., Undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - "German Military Training and mobilzation ". T.cc. 2c.; "Deutsche militaerische Vorbereitung 1934 bis 1942. Ein paar Fakten." T.cc. 51p., 1934-1942 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - "Jugend. Manuskript-Material." T., T.cc. and clippings. Ca. 300p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - "Die Jugendarbeit der Nationalsozialistischen Deutschen Arbeiterpartei (NSDAP)." T. with numerous h. corr. 55p. Another c. T.cc., Undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - "Youth Education in Germany." T. and mimeo. versions. 77p. ea. Two incomplete versions. Mimeo. and T.cc., Undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - "Youth Education in Germany." German versions, duplicates. T. and cc. Ca. 100p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - "Die öffentliche Schulen im Dritten Reich." Mimeo., clippings and T. with h. corr. 56p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - "Politischer Mythos und Realismus." Planned essay volume. Compilation of published essays. 228p., 9p., 1960 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - "Report on the German Refugees and Expellees." T.cc. 245p.; "Monats-Statistik über Flüchtlinge." Charts., Undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - "Sozialistische Nation. Bericht über eine nationalrevolutionäre Widerstandsgruppe gegen Hitler." Dated 1964. T. and T.cc. with numerous h. corr. 36p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - "Sozialistische Nation. Bericht über eine nationalrevolutionäre Widerstandsgruppe gegen Hitler." T. cc. 104p., 1964 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - "Sozialistische Nation. Bericht über eine nationalrevolutionäre Widerstandsgruppe gegen Hitler.". T.cc. 107p, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - "Sozialistische Nation. Bericht, Dokumentation und Selbstkritik einer nationalrevolutionären Widerstandsgruppe gegen Hitler." Part I. T. and clippings. 87p., 1971 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - "Sozialistische Nation: II. Widerstand unter Hitler. Sklavensprache – Illegalitaet – Exil – Opfergang." T. and clippings. 93p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - "Sozialistische Nation. Dokumente." T., mimeo. and clippings. Ca. 100p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - "Studies on National Socialism." Bound volume, containing: "German Military Training and Mobilization .". Mimeo. 49p.; "The Change in the tone of Nazi Propaganda in the German Press in the midst of 1942.". Mimeo. 45p.; "Youth Education in Germany.". Mimeo. 77p.; "The German SS in Arms (Waffen-SS). Appendix.". T.cc., 1942 September; 1943 January; 1943 March; 1943 September (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - "Die Thesen der GSRN [Gruppe Sozialrevolutionäre Nationalisten]." T. and T.cc. with numerous h. corr. 97p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - "Unter'm Fragezeichen." 3 chapters. T. and T.cc., Undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Outlines of various projects. T. and cc. 66p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Manuscripts of Poetry, Short Stories, Essays, Undated; 3.4
    arranged alphabetically.
    This series includes manuscripts of Paetel's poetry, short stories and epigrams, and essayistic writings, and consists of both published and unpublished pieces. The titles listed are working titles and may differ from later published titles.
    - Poetry "Bewährung." T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Poetry "Epigramme." T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Poetry "Flora Germania, das deutsche Hungerbluemelein." T.cc. with corr. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Poetry "Frage." T.cc. 1p.., Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Poetry "Gebet am Morgen." A. 4p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Poetry "Heimkehr?" Dated Paris 1939. T. and T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Poetry "Herbstabend." T. and T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Poetry "Das Lied der deutschen Jugendbewegung." T. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Poetry "Neu Beginnen." T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Poetry "1943, III." T.cc. 1p. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Poetry "Nuernberg VI." T. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Poetry "Das rechte Wort, zur rechten Zeit, im rechten Mund." T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Poetry "Die Saat." T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Poetry "Der Schmerzensmann." T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Poetry "Trotz." Dated "Auf der Flucht auf franzoesischer Landstrasse, 1940." T. and cc. 1p. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Poetry "Unsere Schuld." T.cc. 2p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Poetry "Wider die Lüge." A. 3p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Poetry "Zur Tau-tologie." T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Poetry Untitled poems. T. 3p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Poetry Photocopies of poem texts, some duplicates. 40p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Short stories, epigrams. "Ammon Râ will es!". Alternate titles: "Ammon Ra endet eine Morduntersuchung" and "Wie Ammon Ra entschied". Numerous copies. T. and T.cc. 6p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Short stories, epigrams. "Ballspiele mit Wahrheiten." Short witticisms. T. and cc. 3p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Short stories, epigrams. "Boris. Erzählung." T.cc. 13p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Short stories, epigrams. "BUBU. Die Geschichte einer Katze." T. and T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Short stories, epigrams."Gehören Sie einer Katze?" T. with corr. 5p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Short stories, epigrams. "Der Herr von Nebenan. Ein Trypticon." T., pages numbered 78-108., Undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Short stories, epigrams. "Unter'm Fragezeichen - ? – Geschichten und Aphorismen." Outline. T. 2p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Short stories, epigrams.. "Vier Stunden und 15 Minuten." T. with numerous h. corr. 4p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Short stories, epigrams. "Wuuzi, der Tyrann. Ein Katzengeschichte," alternate title: "Tito terrorisiert mich: Eine Katzengeschichte." T. and T.cc. 7p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Essayistic writings: "Abschied von einem Freund" (Werner Wille). T. with h. corr. 2p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Essayistic writings:"Abstieg vom Gipfel?" T. and T.cc. 5p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Essayistic writings:"Acht Grundsätze." T. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Essayistic writings:"Adlai Stevenson un die neue USA. Strategie bei den Vereinigten Nationen." T.cc. 3p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Essayistic writings: "Afrikas Schatten ueber Harlem." T.cc. 3p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Essayistic writings: " Alabama, die Zivilrechtsfrage und Kennedy." T.cc. 3p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Essayistic writings: "Albert Camus – und der 'Stellvertreter'." T.cc. 2p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Essayistic writings: "Allen Dulles und die C.I.A." T.cc. 3p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Essayistic writings: "Am 9. Juli im Landes Schleswig-Holstein..." T. and cc. 17p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Essayistic writings: "Amerika-Brief." T. with numerous h. corr. 4p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Essayistic writings:"Amerika und der Nahe Osten." T.cc. with corr. 5p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Essayistic writings: "Amerika und die arabische Welt." T.cc. 3p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Essayistic writings:"Amerika und die 'deutschen' Swastikas." T.cc. 3p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Essayistic writings:"Amerika und die deutschen Wahlen." T.cc. 3p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Essayistic writings:"Amerikanisch-Franzoesische Probleme." T.cc. 3p.., Undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Essayistic writings: "Die amerikanische Arbeiterbewegung vor ihrer politischen Chance." T.cc. with h. corr. 6p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Essayistic writings: "Amerikanische Arbeiter-Führer. Vier Kurzportraits." Incomplete text. T. and T.cc. 1p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Essayistic writings: "Amerikanische Jugend im Aufbruch?" T.cc., incomplete. 31p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Essayistic writings: "Der amerikanische Kriminal-Roman." T.cc. 6p., Undated (Box 12, Folder 17)